The behaviors we perform routinely, whether consciously or unconsciously, are our habits.
Each of us has been developing habits for as long as we've been on this planet, however long that may be.
From how we brush our teeth to how we manage our email traffic.
We've formed habits in all aspects of our life by doing the same behaviors over and over again.
This includes the specific habits we have when it comes to learning.
Take a moment right now to reflect on the learning habits you've developed over the course of your life.
For example, I remember when I was studying ancient civilizations for the first time.
My older sister Anna happened to be taking a college seminar on Greek literature.
And all I wanted to do was ask questions, read, and learn more about what she was studying.
I even started practicing Greek.
As a kid, this meant that I always found the time to explore the things I found exciting.
As an adult, we'd call this particular learning habit planning and prioritizing practice, but the idea is the same.
It's important to create the time and space for regular learning.
I have far less pleasant memories from my chemistry class in college.
There were just so many other things I'd rather do than spend hours analyzing the results of my last experiment.
Needless to say, I always found myself writing my lab reports at the last minute, and probably didn't learn as much as I could have.
All these years later, I may have gotten a decent grade in the end, but I don't remember anything.
And the infamous procrastination has stuck with me in the workplace.
I've developed even more learning habits at work over the years.
Some are good, and others… well, there's room for improvement.
For example, a positive learning habit is that I always take the time to share my knowledge and teach others.
Ask my colleagues, Kofi and Maria.
We've spent so many hours together this past year working on an upgrade of our HR systems.
Despite the fact that I proactively share my knowledge with others, funny enough, I'm terrible at asking for help myself.
So I'm working to change that, and instead
develop the better learning habit of reflecting on where I need support, and then actually asking for it.
When it comes to the habits we've cultivated over time, some are purposeful,
like practicing 15 minutes of yoga a day,
and some are subconscious, like driving the same way to work every morning.
And when it comes to learning, research clearly points to the behaviors that are the most beneficial.
If you consciously turn those positive learning behaviors into habits, you will be able to learn more efficiently and effectively.
Why? Because a fresh start can be exciting.
But with time, the novelty fades away and motivation can decrease.
Building good habits automates beneficial behaviors, decreasing the amount of energy you need to keep yourself motivated.
This energy you have conserved can then be applied to grow in other areas.
We call this cognitive efficiency:
your ability to reach learning or other goals through optimal use of mental resources.
In other words, you've saved precious brain power.
In the face of today's constant change, our success is fueled by how quickly we respond to challenges,
acquire new skills, and adapt.
And good learning habits support our ability to do these things.
With each good learning habit we develop, and with each bad one we leave behind,
we're better able to navigate our world, both now and in the future.